DILLON ABBOTT

Full Stack Developer

dragonhunter1230@proto n.me

+1 (713)730-6590

Houston, TX

LinkedIn

Github

I am an innovative and passionate software engineer with 6 years of experience building and maintaining responsive web applications using modern web frontend and backend technology stack and cloud services to make the project another level and meaningful contributions to teams of varying sizes and scopes.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bancor - Front End Developer

January 2018 - June 2021

New York, NY

- Worked on the Payments team to save over 50,000 customers time and improve cash flow through the development of modern, responsive customer experiences
- Led the migration from AWS to GCP for the team to reduce cloud costs by \$260,000 per year
- Worked closely with the product team to re-configure the processing of invoices, saving customers over 125,000 manual hours of work per month
- Mentored 3 junior front end developers on the team on React and documentation best practices within the organization

Pitstop - Frontend Web Developer

August 2016 - November 2017

New York, NY

- Contributed to the in-house UI library to create reusable components that saved over 200 hours of development time per month
- Created a web app MVP for a store delivery management platform with 100+ business customers to create, manage, and monitor deliveries using React and Redux
- Added new features to a meditation app with 5,000+ monthly active users to enable the uploading of audio and video content using React and Redux
- Through A/B testing of different components and combinations improved customer conversion rate by 17%, representing \$500,000+ in incremental annual revenue

EDUCATION

University of Delaware - Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

2012 - 2017

Newark, DE

SKILLS

- Python (Django)
- SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL)
- Cloud (GCP, AWS)
- JavaScript (ES6, React, Redux, Node.js)
- Typescript
- HTML/CSS
- CI/CD